# Claudiu Petre | Software Engineer

LinkedIn: <u>claudiu-p</u> Github: Claudiu-Petre

+44 7721-058-463 claudiu.gpetre@gmail.com 1 Peony Rise, Leeds, LS14 6WL, UK

#### **Profile**

A committed Sofware Engineer with 18 plus months of experience in software development. Aiming to actively contribute to the growth of an organization where my analitical and technical skills could be utilised to the fullest extent. As an Software Engineer I am determined to build and expand my IT skills and experience by assimilating and implementing the latest cutting-edge devlopment tools and procedures.

# **Experience**

Full-stack Software Engineer - Trainee, 'Command Shift' Bootcamp, Manchester, June 2022 - January 2023

'Command Shift' is one of the leading software engineer bootcamps in North of England. It provides an excellent curriculum that builds up a comprehensive understanding and practical skills to enhance innovative software solutions development. The course is led and taught by industry professionals using modern tech principles, through a variety of methods as live lectures, mod sessions, paired programming, self-learning assignments and drop-off sessions.

The skills gained throughout the course:

- · Planning and developing new ideas and solutions in a collaborative environment with tutors and peers via brainstorming, code reviews, stand-ups;
- · Effective communicating and synergistic efforts through paired programming and group projects throughout the software development lifecycle;
- Designing and creating front-end applications linked to back-end via Express. JS APIs, SQL database and CRUD operations.
- · Developing resourcefulness during personal study and coding sessions by researching, filtering and implementing the most effective solutions;
- Continuing personal development and pursue additional certification with guidance from experienced mentors;

# **Projects**

# Meteorologist:

A React web app that allows users to search for the weather conditions by querying an open source API (openweathermap.org/api). The app is built in React exploring most of the its features: Functional components, Context, Helpers, Hooks, State management. Data retrieval is done by using Axios and the testing is done through Jest. The styling was applied using CSS features.

An API the users can utilize to mange their own library by employing CRUD operations on a SQL databse built using MySQL Workbench. The app is developed on Node.js with Express.js and tested by Jest, Chai, Mocha Bootcamp, Manchester, and Supertest. Each step of the API lifecycle and file changes were monitored using Postman and Nodemon. The containerization was managed using Docker.

### Mapper:

The app facilitates users' tracking of outdoor activities in an interactive mode using Leaflet, a JavaScript leading open-source library for interactive maps. Structured in HTML and the logic and functionality being provided by Javascript (classes, constructors, prototypes, functions and arrays) makes the app both solid and responsive. The UI experience is designed in CSS;

Other projects: Do\$her, Cruise-ships, No.It, Flips,

#### **Work history**

### Site Manager, Brackenhill Primary School (UK) November 2021 - present

- Used Smartlog V5- cloud based Fire and H & S compliance management software;
- Managed the Maintenance and Cleaning team (8 people);
- Liaised with a variety of suppliers and contractors for on rolling projects.

### PCV Driver, First Yorkshire Group (UK) July 2014 - October 2021

- Delivered company's services to clients and liaised with third parties;
- Attended professional development training programme;

#### Career Adviser, Close to YOUth Association (RO) June 2009 - August 2012

- Designed career orientation curriculum in accordance with project objectives;
- Delivered one to one and group career orientation sessions;

#### **Skills**

Javascript React **HTML CSS** 

Express.Js SOL- MySOL **TDD Jest** Python

Agile methodologies Debugging Docker

> **GITHub** Postman CI/CD

Self Motivated Resilient Details focused Problem solving Analytical **Team Communication** Good sense of humour

#### **Education**

# Full-stack Engineer,

'Command Shift' 2023

### GCSEs,

English (A); Maths (B); Leeds City College, 2016

M. B. A., Craiova University, 2006

B. Ec. Management, Craiova University, 2003

# Certification

The Complete Javascript (300 hrs), Udemy; 2023

React - Beginners (2 hrs), Udemy; 2023

The Complete Python Pro Bootcamp (100

days); in progress